

SIGFRID STJÄRNHOLM

Physics student & developer

Weden Uppsala, Sweden

☑ sigge.stjarnholm@gmail.com

A two-year programme at Uppsala University, specializing in the Nuclear and Particle

Physics track. The programme reinforces the knowledge within fundamental physics, and

with the course collection of mine I have chosen to put a lot of weight on the experimental

Co-author of a paper published in Astroparticle Physics, and author of conference

proceedings for two international conferences (ICRC 2021 and ARENA 2022)

• Recipient of the award 'Best student presentation' at The Student Conference in

• Recipient of the scholarship Hallberg, Malin and Ivar, which is awarded to a 'talented

Solid Mechanics

Automatic Control I

Electronics I

• Student representative in the Programme Advisory Board for the Masters's

Advanced Particle Physics

Quantum Field Theory

involves plenty of rigour in mathematics and a lot of programming.

Bachelor's degree (Bachelor's Programme in Physics)

Electric Measurement Techniques

Symmetry and Group Theory in Physics

A three-year programme at Uppsala University covering a large portion the fundamental

physics - from classical mechanics to advanced quantum physics. The programme also

Student representative in the Programme Advisory Board for the Bachelor's

• Recipient of three prices from the Mathematical Society at Uppsala University for

distinctive performance in the courses Geometry and Calculus I, Geometry and



github.com/kladdy

sigfrid.me

CAREER SUMMARY

As a student at both gymnasial and University level, I have been engaged in various concils related to my studies. Working as a software consultant alongside my studies have yielded me great experience in how projects develop and has also allowed me to test the waters in a large variety of programming paradigms.

EDUCATION

2021 - Present

Achievements:

student'

Accelerators and Detectors

Statistical Methods in Physics

Computer Programming II

Industrial Management

2018 - 2021

Achievements:

aspect of particle physics.

Programme in Physics

Selection of courses (so far):

Science and Technology 2021

Master's degree (Master's Programme in Physics)

Uppsala University

Classical Electrodynamics

Uppsala University

Fluid Mechanics

Solid State Physics F

p Particle physics

Quantum physics Nuclear physics

Simulations

INTERESTS

Experiments

Open-source

SKILLS & TOOLS Software Python C# / C++ JS / TS / Node.js SQL HTML / CSS LaTeX Git HTTP / DNS Hardware Arduino / Raspberry Pi

Computer assembling

Circuits

Presentations

Other

Structuring work Getting things done Collaborative Independent

Giving speeches

Responsible

HOBBIES

Mountain hiking

Bread baking Skiing

റ് Cycling

Computer hardware

Recipient of Melanderhjelm's scholarship from the Faculty of Science and

Vice Chairman in the Student Faculty Council for Physics students

Technology at Uppsala University

Calculus III, and Fourier Analysis

Programme in Physics

Analytical Mechanics Electromagnetic Field Theory **Complex Analysis Computer Programming I** Geometry and Calculus I, II & III **Electromagnetism Elementary Particle Physics** Fourier Analysis Linear Algebra II Mechanics KF & III Mathematical Statistics KF Mathematical Methods of Physics Physics Project I & II **Medical Physics Nuclear Physics** Ordinary Differential Equations I Physics Project with a Research Basis Quantum Mechanics **Quantum Physics** Physics and Finance Scientific Computing KF & II Special Relativity **Statistical Mechanics** Thermodynamics

Waves and Optics

Selection of courses:

Björknäsgymnasiet

2015 - 2018 A three-year programme at Björknäsgymnasiet involving the natural sciences.

Gymnasium (Natural Science Programme)

Achievements:

- Chairman in the Programme Advisory Board for the Natural Science Programme • Chairman in the Student Council for Björknäsgymnasiet
- Scholarship from the Natural Science Programme for distinctive performance Attendee of a 2-week long internship at CERN (HSSIP)
- Finalist in Wallenbergs fysikpris (Swedish national physics competition) and competitor in the Nordic-Baltic Physics Olympiad (NBPhO)
- Attendee of Berzeliusdagarna, a weekend-seminar for students interested in chemistry
- Attendee of Rymdforskarskolan, a 2-week programme at Esrange space center

Self-employed at

ENGAGEMENTS

Stjärnholm Consulting Banner carrier for

> Norrland's nation (Student association in Uppsala) **1** Test supervisor at the

Swedish Scholastic Aptitude Test (Högskoleprovet, SweSAT) Election worker at the

Hometown ambassador for Uppsala University

2022 Swedish general

election

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present With a part-time employment during the Master's Programme, I have worked as a research

Research assistant and teaching assistant

output voltages, as well as battery capacities.

Uppsala University

assistant at the Department of Physics and Astronomy at Uppsala University. I am involved within the Astroparticle Physics research group, coupled to the Division for High Energy Physics (HEP). I have also worked as a teacher assistant at the Department of Information Technology. **Involvements:**

Teacher assistant during fall 2022 in the course Application-Oriented Deep Learning

- in Physics, a course which introduces machine learning, deep learning, and neural networks with a focus on applications in physics. Research tasks related to using neural networks to reconstruct neutrino properties from radio detector data. The work is to be used for an upcoming detector station at
- the South Pole called IceCube-Gen2 radio, and was a continuation of my bachelor's thesis. • Research regarding the use of wind generators and batteries that can handle the extreme cold at the South Pole. The tasks included measuring of generator losses,
- Teaching assistant in Computer Programming II during spring 2022. The course was given in Python, and the tasks included correcting assignments and aiding students with the course material.

Thave lived for

STATISTICS

23 yr, 4 mo, 17 d, 11 h, 10 min, 1 s I have donated 21 240 008 665 827

thrombocytes during 36 sessions

Jolix is an IT consulting company specializing in E-commerce applications. At Jolix, I have

2016 - Present

Software consulting

worked on plenty of projects within varying programming environments. The company

Jolix AB

also runs a small electronics store in Boden named pålyset.se, in which I have worked as a clerk. **Projects:** Backend development of a checkout system for organizations using C#, Node.js &

microservices

- Backend development of a message listener for IoT-devices reporting back to a central hub using Node.js
- Integrating customers to a Storm API in C# • Frontend development of a dashboard web application for E-commerce admins

Technologies used: .NET (4.5 & Core) Python Node.js C# HTML CSS

Test-driven development Unit testing Microservices React Redux Swagger

Javascript/Typescript]

Git

JSON

Event organizer Lise Meitner-dagarna 2019 - 2021

experiments, exhibitions and lectures by prominent physicists in a variety of fields. The organizing group consists of 4 members, and about 130 students from all over Sweden attend the event each year. Roles:

Lise Meitner-dagarna is a yearly weekend-seminar in Stockholm for high-school students

interested in physics. During three intensive days, the students get to partake in laboratory

- Head of administration (2019 2020): Bookings for hotel, catering, and trips for the
- whole event. Managing registrations for schools, students, and exhibitors. • Head of communication and marketing (2021): Designs for mailings. Communication with schools and students. Upkeep of the website. Photography and social media.